## Achmad Yuneda Alfajr

## Software Engineer

• yunedaalfajr@gmail.com • 628980023612 • <u>Linkedin</u> • <u>Github</u>

#### **SUMMARY**

Software Engineer with 2 years of experience with varying degrees between front end, back end and automation. Capable of working with a variety of technology and software solutions and managing databases. I like to learn programming with new technology.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

• Languages : Javascript, Typescript, Python, Go, Kotlin

• Technologies : React JS, Next JS, Node, Express, Nest JS, Github, Jira, GCP, Firebase, Selenium, Redis,

Google Cloud Pub

Other : Postgre SQL, MySQL, VM, gerkhin, Big Query.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

GOCEMENT Surabaya, Indonesia
Data Engineer 02/2024-12/2024

- Developed python scripts to automate the process using GCP Cloud Function.
- Ensured the quality and reliability of products, services, or processes.
- Analyzed issues related to a data warehouse and database.
- Provided support and maintenance.
- Delivered data visualization solutions using Looker.
- Created and managed table data in BigQuery through join operations, leveraging automation and scheduled queries in GCP.
- Integrated Jira automation with BigQuery to provide data for analysis.
- Designed and implemented dashboards using Looker to enable company analysis for monitoring business processes
  and evaluating sales data, utilizing BigQuery as the data source.
- Integrated Jira with external systems to send WhatsApp notifications to designated targets when specific events occur, such as issue creation or linked issues aligned with defined business processes.

SFS GROUP
Surabaya, Indonesia
Web Developer
03/2023-02/2024

- Joined the IT department.
- Collaborated closely with the product teams using jira
- Contributed to the development of broadcast message system with pubsub
- Handled for both the cloud function and frontend project using react, typescript, firebase, redis.
- Used state management like redux and context to handle the data in the front end
- Used ui library like MUI and Ant Design to help the process of slicing front end page
- Collaborated with the QA team to write clear Gherkin scenarios and select automation tools supporting Gherkin and Kotlin, like Cucumber, and set up the development environment.
- Integrated a payment gateway for both frontend and backend systems to support subscription management and cancellation using Xendit, including handling detailed invoice information for each billing cycle.

## PT AKSAMEDIA MULIA DIGITAL Fullstack Web Developer

Surabaya, Indonesia 11/2022-03/2023

Developed visually appealing user interfaces that enhance user experience using React, TypeScript, and Chakra UI

- Developed high-performance, scalable, and maintainable full-stack applications using NestJS, GraphQL, Apollo Server, and TypeORM
- Employed Swagger for seamless API documentation, enabling clear and comprehensive documentation for developers, stakeholders, and end-users alike
- Utilized packages such as Passport, bcrypt, and JWT for robust authentication and authorization
- Developed a notification module that utilized push notifications, leveraging the Firebase Cloud Messaging (FCM) token system.
- Integrated OTP WhatsApp using Twilio services.

#### **INTERNSHIP**

#### PT AKSAMEDIA MULIA DIGITAL

Surabaya, Indonesia 09/2022-10/2022

### Fullstack Web Developer

- Implemented a system where users could request verification status.
- Developed a business group module enabling management of premium and non-premium content for verified and non-verified users.

PT ANDROMEDIA Surabaya, Indonesia
Full Stack Engineer 08/2022-12/2022

- Implemented database using PostgreSQL.
- Implemented Backend using Node.js platform. with and Prisma ORM
- Implemented Frontend using React and/or Tailwind platforms.

#### **EDUCATION**

# UNIVERSITAS PEMBANGUNAN NASIONAL "VETERAN" JAWA TIMUR Bachelor of Engineering, Major in Computer Science

Surabaya, Indonesia 2019-2023

- GPA: 3.92 (Magna cumlaude)
- Thesis: Classification Of Distracted Driver Using Support Vector Machine Based On Principal Component Analysis Feature Reduction And Convolutional Neural Network
- Publish paper Classification Of Distracted Driver Using Support Vector Machine Based On Principal Component Analysis Feature Reduction And Convolutional Neural Network nn Jurnal Komputer Dan Informatika
- Publish paper Website Development to Display Crypto Coin Prices with Application Programming Interface on Jurnal Teknik Informatika dan Sistem Informasi

#### **ORGANIZATIONS**

#### Mobile Developer Community (Vice President)

- Assisted lead organizer in all matters within the community.
- Managed the coordination of the community team and all its members.
- Gave lesson on learning Flutter with Dart

### LICENSES AND CERTIFICATIONS

- Belajar Dasar Structured Query Language (SQL) Dicoding
- Junior Web Developer Badan Nasional Sertifikasi Profesi
- Belajar Dasar-Dasar DevOps Dicoding
- AWS Academy Graduate AWS Academy Machine Learning Foundations
- Belajar Membuat Aplikasi Web Dengan React Dicoding
- Python Fundamental for Data Science
- Belajar Machine Learning untuk Pemula Dicoding
- Belajar Membuat front-End Web untuk Pemula Dicoding
- Memulai Pemrograman dengan Python Dicoding